For the road images you've seen, you know that they're all composed of red,
我们已经知道 之前所见到的公路图像全部是由
green, and blue values or RGB.
红色 绿色和蓝色的数值组成的 或者简称为 RGB
And in the past, you've used some combination of masking and
此前 我们在这些 RGB 值上同时使用了掩膜和颜色阈值
color thresholds on these RGB values to pick out bright white lane pixels.
目的在于选出属于亮白色车道线的像素
And this lane detection can work well alongside gradient detection
这种车道检测方法与梯度检测协同工作
which relies on grayscale intensity measurements.
梯度检测依赖于测得的灰度强度
However, RGB thresholding doesn't work that well in images that include varying
然而 不同光线条件的图像中 或车道颜色为其他颜色（例如黄色）时
light conditions or when lanes are a different color like yellow.
RGB 阈值处理效果不佳
Let me show you what I mean.
具体解释一下
Take this image of a road.
以这张公路图像为例
We can break it down into it's separate RGB components
我们可以将其分解为单独的 RGB 分量
which are often called channels.
这些分量通常称为颜色通道
Here are the three channels represented in grayscale intensity.
这是采用灰度强度代表的三个颜色通道
The brighter pixels indicate higher values of red, green, or blue,
亮度更大的像素分别表示
respectively.
更红 更绿 或更蓝
Looking at the lane lines, you can see that the red and
看看车道线 你会看到白色和黄色车道线
green channels are high for both the white and yellow lane lines.
在红色和绿色通道较亮
But if we look at the blue channel,
但如果观察蓝色通道
there's almost no blue component in the yellow lane.
会发现黄色车道线内几乎没有蓝色分量
So the R and G channels will be the most useful for isolating both white and
因此 红色 (R) 和绿色 (G) 通道对于分离出
yellow lane pixels.
白色和黄色的车道像素最有用
But you can also see that the red and green values change
不过你也能看到 这些图像靠后区域亮度不同
under different levels of brightness at the back of the image.
红色和绿色分量发生了变化
They get lower under shadow and
在阴影区域的值变得更低
don't consistently recognize the lane under extreme brightness.
并且在极亮情况下 无法连续地识别车道线
Let's see if there's a better way to detect these lanes.
我们看一下 有没有更好的检测这些车道线的办法
There are many other ways to represent the colors in an image
除了用红 绿 蓝色通道表示以外
besides just composed of red, green and blue values.
还有很多其他颜色表示方式
These different color representations are often called color spaces.
这些不同的色彩表示方式通常称为色彩空间
RGB is red, green, blue color space.
RGB 是红绿蓝色彩空间
You can think of this as a 3D space where
你可以把它看做一个三维空间
any color can be represented by a 3D coordinate of R, G, and B values.
在该空间里 任何颜色都可以通过红绿蓝的三维坐标值表示
There's also HSV color space, for hue, saturation, and value.
此外 还有 HSV 色彩空间 代表色相 饱和度和明度
And there's HLS, for hue, lightness, and saturation.
以及 HLS 色彩空间 代表色相 亮度和饱和度
These are some of the most commonly used color spaces in image analysis.
它们是图像分析中最常用的色彩空间
For both of these, H has a range from 0 to 179 for
上述两种色彩空间呈圆柱形
degrees around the cylindrical color space.
色相 H 的范围为 0 到 179 度
And you can see details about the mathematical conversion from RGB to HLS
下面我们来详细讲解从 RGB 到 HLS 空间的
space in the notes below.
数学转换细节
We'll be going through an example in HLS color space.
以 HLS 色彩空间为例
This isolates the lightness or L component of each pixel in an image.
这种色彩空间可区分出图像中每个像素的亮度值 或称为 L 分量
And this is the component that varies the most under different lighting
L 分量在不同的照明条件下
conditions.
取值变化最大
But the H and S channels stay fairly consistent under shadow or
但是 H 和 S 通道在阴影或过亮的情况下
excessive brightness.
几乎保持不变
And if we use these channels only and
如果我们只使用这两条通道
discard the information in the L channel, we should be able to detect
并舍弃 L 通道的信息 就能检测到
different colors of lane lines more reliably than in RGB color space.
不同颜色的车道线 而且比使用 RGB 色彩空间更可靠
Here's that same RGB road image converted to HLS color space.
这是同一张公路图像 从 RGB 转换成了 HLS 色彩空间
If we break it down into the separate H, L, and S channels,
如果我们将其分解为单独的 H L S 通道
we can really see the difference between this color space and RGB color space.
我们就能实实在在看到这种色彩空间和 RGB 色彩空间之间的不同
Here, it looks like the S channel detects lane lines pretty well,
S 通道能非常好地检测车道线
as well as dark sections of the H channel.
以及 H 通道的暗色部分
And we can use this channels to create a smart color threshold
我们可以使用这个通道创建一个更巧妙的颜色阈值
that reliably detects lane line pixels of different colors.
这样就能稳定地检测不同颜色的车道线
Let see an example of color thresholding in code next.
下面 我们将展示一个颜色阈值的代码示例